Miles Johan Bailey-Braendgaard, Software Engineer

Oxford, United Kingdom, +447391894290, milesbb101@gmail.com

Nationality	UK, Denmark (EU), and US	
LINKS	Portfolio, LinkedIn, Github	
PROFILE	Software Engineer with a background in computer science, biomechanics, arts, and engineering who is ready to develop, learn, and become a proactive member of your team.	
	Have experience adapting to new languages, IDE's, and technologies and applying them to cross-disciplinary problems.	
	Technologies I often work with include: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, AWS (S3, Lambda, ECS, and others), React.js, Node.js, CSS, HTML, MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redux, Three.js, Bootstrap, Git/Github/Gitlabs, Vercel, Netlify, JIRA, Confluence, Teams, Agile Methodology.	
EXPERIENCE		
Jan 2023 — Present	Junior Software Engineer, Aurora Energy Research	Oxford, UK
	 Full-stack responsibilities within a complex architecture of event-driven serverless Typescript and Python based micro-services and seamless React micro-frontends using MySQL and AWS Cloud services including Lambda, S3, and ECS Developing fintech SaaS/MaaS (Modelling-as-a-Service) software solutions that handle bulk data and deliver bespoke financial simulations and analysis to worldwide internal and external users. Based in (Oxford) head office Software Engineering department often working inter-disciplinarily with analysts, modellers, and product leads 	
Nov 2021 — Jan 2022	Intern Prosthetist/Orthotist, Aktiv Ortopedteknik	Lund, Sweden
	 Clinical placement working hands-on with patients and collaborating in multidisciplinary teams within Skåne University-Hosptial. Experience handling delicate scenarios and design problems under time pressure including biohazard scenarios, war-related injuries, language interpretation, and healthcare work during the COVID-19 pandemic Adapted quickly to new patient records databases and software, gained in-depth experience including with Upper Limb Prosthetics. 	
Aug 2020 — Aug 2021	Writer, EDIT Newspaper	Jönköping, Sweden
	 Wrote English and Swedish language articles on topics such as social issues and art for both the physical and online editions of the Jönköping University student newspaper. 	
May 2019 — Dec 2019	Software Developer, Culture Hustle	Bournemouth, UK
	 Developed an AI 'Chatbot' (Primarily in AIML 2.0, HTML, and JavaScript) for the company to aid in marketing and customer support and UX. 	
Mar 2019 — Jun 2019	Production Assistant, Culture Hustle	Bournemouth, UK
	 Assistant to British artist, creator, and activist Stuart Semple in both manufacture of commercial art supply products and maintenance of art studio space. 	
Jun 2015	Software Engineering Work Experience, Siemens Traffic Solutions	Poole, UK
	• Shadowed software engineering department whilst learning about and designing j algorithms in C#.	unction traffic sorting
EDUCATION		

• High-intensive highly-rated Full-Stack Development Bootcamp (Formerly known as Strive School) focusing on MERN and PERN stack including topics such as Javascript, Typescript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL, Cryptography, and Authentication.

Aug 2019 — Jun 2022

BSc Prosthetics and Orthotics, Jönköping University

Jönköping, Sweden

- International Society of Prosthetics and Orthotics (ISPO) Accredited Program
- Clinical, tech, and research focused including modules on statistics
- Dissertation on the application, accuracy, and reliability of 3D scanning devices and spatial data processing software in the field

Jul 2017

UNIQ Oxford University Summer School

Oxford, UK

• Official summer school run by the university with specialisation in Engineering and Engineering software including MATLAB and C++

Sep 2014 — Jul 2018

A-Levels and GCSEs, Poole Grammar School

Poole, UK

- 3 A-Levels: Maths, Electronics, and German
- 13 GCSEs: including Maths, Further Maths, Computer Science, and Electronics

AWARDS

Jul 2016

Arkwright Engineering Scholarship

Competitive UK-based scholarship sponsoring school and extra-curricular projects in Engineering,
 Computing, and Technical Design, including a placement at UK-based defence firm Ultra Electronics.

SKILLS

- I work daily with Typescript and Python though I have some experience with C# and Solidity and would be able to quickly learn and adapt to other languages/frameworks/cloud services as required
- Experience with 3D modelling, scanning, printing, and gait analysis software including Canfit, Paromed, Autodesk, Vxelements, Visual3D, and Qualisys
- People- and detail-oriented, with experience organising and hosting events, trips, and student support in the Jönköping University Student Union and at work

LANGUAGES

English Swedish Native speaker Highly proficient

Danish German Highly proficient

Good working knowledge

HOBBIES

Languages - trying desperately to learn Mandarin; Music - play the bass and piano; Hiking- every other weekend;